Hello everybody, and welcome to our
first episode of John Kiriakou's
briefing room. I'm John Kiriakou. Here
in the briefing room, we aim to bring
you news and commentary without
political bias. It's all about the
analysis. We give you the facts, and
then we talk about what those facts
mean. Even before we begin, I want to
thank you for being here. It is
literally only because of you that we
can make a go of this. So, please do me
the personal favor of liking,
commenting, rating, reviewing, and
sharing the podcast with your friends
and family. It would really mean a lot.
So, what's in the news today? Actually,
there's a lot in the news today. Um
Our first topic is and should be the
Iran war. Fighting has resumed again.
The US and Iran are trading strikes,
serious strikes, strikes that are
killing people. The United States is
bombing military targets all around
Iran. The Iranians are bombing US
military targets, so far primarily in
Qatar and Kuwait. They're also hitting
Bahrain and Oman. They fired missiles at
Jordan yesterday. Those missiles did not
impact anything.
But, this is a big deal. It's It's not
It's not just a temporary conflagration.
This This is a real war. Uh this all
started because Well, it didn't start at
all, reignited because the Iranians
attacked a Cypriot-flagged
uh ship in the Strait of Hormuz. They uh
hit the engine room, apparently with a
drone. One uh seaman went overboard and
is still missing and now presumed dead.
At the same time that this is all
happening, Washington lost one of its
most influential foreign policy players
over the last three decades. That was
Senator Lindsey Graham. I have been
tough on Lindsey Graham over the years.
I have always maintained
that on Capitol Hill there are
workhorses
and there are showhorses.
A workhorse is a member of the House or
a member of the Senate who actually
writes legislation and is a substantive
expert on something.
A showhorse is a member of Congress who
just runs in front of the nearest camera
and bloviates about whatever happens to
be in the news. That was Lindsey Graham.
I don't mean to speak ill of the dead,
but Lindsey Graham
has so much blood on his hands over the
last 30 years that I don't think we
should be celebrating him.
Lindsey Graham died on Saturday night at
his home on Capitol Hill
just hours after returning from a trip
to Kiev. He is one of the strongest
supporters of the Ukrainian government
on Capitol Hill. Medical examiners say
that the cause was a perforated aorta.
Uh he apparently had um arteriosclerosis
that he didn't know about. His arteries
were clogged. And the bottom line is
that he had a massive heart attack.
To understand how sudden this was, just
hours before he died, Graham was
speaking with President Trump and
preparing to appear on NBC's Meet the
Press the following morning, Sunday
morning. He was booked and then suddenly
he was dead. In the end Trump went on
Meet the Press uh in his place. Graham
was not just simply one of the Senate's
loudest talks. He was one of the few
lawmakers with direct personal access to
President Trump and to Israeli Prime
Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. That made
him a player in foreign policy
automatically.
He often served as an unofficial
backchannel between Washington and
Jerusalem. But but Graham was so
pro-Israel as to be irrational.
Um
his death now sort of changes things on
Capitol Hill for a number of reasons.
Number one,
uh
Israel has lost its most vocal
supporter.
He really was its most vocal supporter.
Number two, Ukraine has lost its most
vocal supporter. Number three,
the Republican Party has lost really
what amounted to a Trump whisperer,
somebody who had Donald Trump's ear
and who who could convince him
to do things.
But let's look for a minute at
the history of Lindsey Graham. Lindsey
Graham was in the House of
Representatives for many years before
being elected to the Senate three terms
ago, 18 years ago. Uh he was one of the
leaders of the
House impeachment of President Bill
Clinton. Made a name for himself there,
ran for the Senate, got elected to the
Senate, and has been easily reelected
ever since. Now, he fended off a rather
strong primary challenge a couple of
months ago,
but still with well over 50%. And he was
a shoo-in for reelection in November.
But Lindsey Graham
was a chameleon.
This is This is a word that I've used to
describe him
multiple times over the years.
Whatever happened to be in vogue,
whatever foreign policy goal happened to
be popular,
there was Lindsey Graham.
If there was one thing that Lindsey
Graham loved loved loved more than
anything else, it was war.
He was a lieutenant colonel in the Judge
Advocate General's Office in the Army.
Uh he
served for decades,
but he never saw a war that he didn't
want to jump into with both feet. And
I'm talking about Afghanistan, Iraq,
Libya, Syria, Ukraine, Gaza. He loved
them all. And he was one of the biggest
proponents of a wildly inflated defense
budget on Capitol Hill.
The current defense budget is $1
trillion. That's That's more than the
next nine largest countries combined.
And he wanted to increase that by 50%
next year.
In 1 year.
He didn't care if
children were starving. He didn't care
that his state was near the bottom of
the entire collection of 50 states in
public education. He didn't care.
So long as we had state-of-the-art
weapons and weapon systems, ships, F-35
fighter jets, whatever the Pentagon
wanted, Lindsey Graham made sure
the Pentagon had.
Lindsey Graham was also the chairman of
the Senate Budget Committee and the
number two on both the Appropriations
Committee and the
um
Judiciary Committee.
And so he played a leading role in
pushing Donald Trump's Supreme Court
nominees through the process.
Getting back to Israel here.
For Israel,
Lindsey Graham's death removes one of
Benjamin Netanyahu's closest and most
reliable allies in Congress. In in in
both of these conflicts, whether it's
Gaza or Iran that we're talking about,
and going all the way back to the Iraq
war, he was always more than happy for
the conflict to escalate. And
frequently, he was a proponent on
Capitol Hill, sometimes the only
proponent, for sending in ground troops.
His death, though,
is an enormous potential gift for the
people of Gaza. This is someone who, in
the Meet the Press green room, would be
on the phone with Benjamin Netanyahu
asking if there was any information that
he could reveal on the air. Seriously.
This is what he did. Here's an example
of how he would talk on that show.
>> So, when we were faced with destruction
as a nation after Pearl Harbor fighting
the Germans and the Japanese, we decided
to end the war by the bombing Hiroshima
and Nagasaki with nuclear weapons. That
was the right decision. Give Israel the
bombs they need to end the war they
can't afford to lose and work with them
to minimize casualties. Can I say this?
Why is it okay for America to not to to
drop two nuclear bombs on Hiroshima and
Nagasaki to end their existential threat
war? Why was it okay for us to do that?
I thought it was okay. So, Israel, do
whatever you have to do to survive as a
Jewish state.
>> Ay, yay, yay. Where do you even start
with something like that? First of all,
historians are unanimous now that it was
not necessary for the United States to
drop nuclear bombs on Hiroshima and
Nagasaki. The war was essentially over.
Yes, we would have had to have launched
a ground war, but the Japanese were
broken. Besides, the Soviets The Soviets
were moving in from the north. The war
was done.
Dropping nuclear bombs on Hiroshima and
Nagasaki was a political decision.
And it was a terrible one.
More than 100,000 people were vaporized
by those bombs, not to even mention the
the thousands and thousands, tens of
thousands of people who developed
cancers later from the nuclear fallout.
But,
Lindsey Graham is advocating
allowing Israel
to use nuclear bombs
on its own people.
On innocent civilians, women, children,
the elderly,
populated areas.
I I don't know anybody in his right mind
that would advocate for something like
that. And and furthermore, let's take it
the next step. If it's okay for the
United States to use nuclear weapons and
okay for Israel to use nuclear weapons,
then why wouldn't it be okay for the
Russians to use nuclear weapons?
Or the Chinese, or the Indians and the
Pakistanis.
The French for that matter, the British.
It would usher in an entire new world.
It's insanity. This is an insane
position perpetrated by Lindsey Graham.
And here's how Benjamin Netanyahu
reacted to news of Lindsey Graham's
Lindsey Graham's death. Let's go to that
video.
>> And I think one or once or twice he got
his way. But let me tell you,
the last conversation I had with him, I
said, "Lindsey,
we've come of age.
We have a a robust economy. We can we
can take care of our own financing our
own weapons for the defense of Israel
and defense of our common interest with
America. So, I'm going to phase out the
support the military support for Israel
the over
a period of years and bring it down to
zero. We can do it."
And he went ballistic. He said, "No way,
you can't do that." Because he was so
concerned with our security, which he
believed was your security, that he
actually fought the Prime Minister of
Israel on keeping America's aid or
actually increasing it.
And that tells you what kind of a person
this this extraordinary
extraordinary friend was.
>> Yeah, that says a lot right there. Uh
you know, there's there's kind of a side
story to this, too. Uh
to to Benjamin Netanyahu's comments just
now.
He took a
political shot at uh
at Democrats. It was very, very subtle,
and I think most Americans probably
missed it. But what he said was that
he wants to phase out American
aid, specifically military aid, to
Israel over the coming years. And
Lindsey Graham was against that and
because our security is the same as
their security, blah, blah, blah, blah.
He did that on purpose though. He said
that on purpose because he's trying to
figure out a way to turn American public
opinion back in support of Israel.
He knows that
that most Americans hate foreign aid. I
actually happen to like foreign aid. I
think that
I think that it buys us soft power that,
you know,
is is well worth the cost. But the
conventional wisdom in the United States
today, and this has been true for for
the last 20 or 25 years, Americans don't
like foreign aid. Well, the number one
recipient of American foreign aid is
Israel.
But the thing is is if you are going to
be co-located
uh with American
uh
military officials in the Pentagon or
with intelligence officials in the CIA
and you've got spies spread out all over
the country stealing American secrets
anyway
and you're a first world country with a
first world economy
you don't need the aid.
And so, I think that Benjamin
Netanyahu's calculation here is
let's spread the word among the American
people that we don't want this foreign
aid anymore. You guys keep it. You spend
it on yourselves. We're going to be
okay. We'll we'll tough it out. We'll be
okay. Well,
Israel is a is a socialist welfare state
anyway.
They've gone generations living on the
the teat of the American taxpayer.
So, don't don't think that Benjamin
Netanyahu is doing us any favor here.
He's not.
Well, getting back to Lindsey Graham.
Now that he's died, we are in this
unique situation where his work
portfolio has essentially been revealed.
This is fascinating. A reporter for
Axios by the name of Barak Ravid was
very close to Lindsey Graham.
And he just
released essentially Lindsey Graham's
dying wishes and also his proposed
arrangement to end fighting between the
US and Iran even as we're getting into a
new period of fighting with Iran. His
key to solve the region
the problem across the region ran
through
highly unpopular Saudi leader, de facto
leader, Crown Prince Mohammad bin
Salman.
Let's check out this Axios piece. Here's
what he reported from his conversations
with Lindy Lindsey Graham.
The White House is preparing for what
could become a multi-day or even
multi-week exchange of fire with Iran
over the Strait of Hormuz.
The length and severity of the new
campaign hinges entirely on Tehran's
next moves, US officials tell Axios. Why
it matters. A war that began with the
goal of degrading Iran's missile
capabilities and destroying what
remained of its nuclear program has
evolved into an open-ended fight over
the world's most important energy choke
point.
A US official said the current
escalation could last a day or two, a
week, or a month depending on whether
Iran continues its attacks on commercial
ships in the Strait of Hormuz.
"We're going to slap them a bit so they
understand we're not around." the US
official said. Okay, let's take a break
right there.
It's pretty clear Lindsey Graham is the
source
for Barak Ravid Barak
what's his name Ravid. It's pretty
clear.
Um Lindsey Graham has said these things
publicly using the same language, the
same lingo, the same word structure.
And the thing is is Lindsey Graham
here's a guy with a lifetime of military
uh experience,
a a lifetime of political experience on
Capitol Hill dealing with the military
and with uh foreign policy.
And he still thinks that a country of
nearly 93 million people,
Iran,
the size of the whole of Western Europe,
and with the support of Russia and
China,
can be brought
to defeat in a day or two?
A week?
Or a month?
That's how we got into 20-year-long wars
in Afghanistan and and Iraq.
Because we listened to idiots
like Lindsey Graham.
Moving on. Driving the news,
diplomacy has stalled for now, and
military pressure is back at the center
of President Trump's strategy. Trump
said Wednesday,
the 60-day ceasefire outlined in the
memorandum of understanding was over
after an exchange of fire triggered by
Iranian attacks on commercial ships. The
US then launched a second round of
strikes near the Strait of Hormuz
including attacks on infrastructure
targets inside Iran for the first time
in months. Iran retaliated with attacks
on US bases in Kuwait and Bahrain while
insisting it would not back down from
its claim to control the strait. The
bottom line here,
and this is a clear bottom line,
we can't beat Iran.
Nobody can beat Iran. First of all,
the culture is the 7,000 years old.
Secondly, they live in the area.
Third, the nature of warfare has
changed. Think of it this way.
We sent two aircraft carrier strike
forces, also called aircraft carrier
battle groups.
It's an aircraft carrier full of fighter
jets, and they take with them between 11
and 12 ships. Either
either 11 or 12 ships.
The Iranians are fighting with suicide
drones.
Suicide drones cost between 5 and 10,000
dollars to make. You just strap
explosives onto them, and you fly them
into a target.
You can't defend yourself from something
like that.
If if you have something like the
Israeli Iron Dome, let's say.
That's That's fine. You can shoot things
out of the air. You can shoot down
incoming missiles or what have you.
But you can't shoot down 5,000 incoming
drones. You don't have 5,000 missiles.
Similarly, how in the world are you
going to protect an aircraft carrier
against suicide drones that are just
going to fly into its side?
The Gulf Arab countries
are beside themselves over this. I was
in Kuwait a few months ago. I was in Abu
Dhabi, and I was in Dubai a few months
ago.
I also have friends who are members of
five of the six royal families. I don't
have any Saudi royal family contacts,
but I have close contacts in all the
other royal families.
And unanimously, they are asking
themselves, "Why do we have these
American bases here?"
Right? There are army bases in
Kuwait, Saudi Arabia, and Oman.
Bahrain is the headquarters of the Fifth
Fleet of the US Navy.
Uh
Qatar has the
largest US Air Force base in the world,
anywhere in the world.
And in the United Arab Emirates, we have
ground troops, we have air troops, we
have navies, uh sailors.
And we can't stop Iran from attacking
these these countries, these friends of
ours.
And so, they're beginning to think,
maybe we should make our own peace with
the Iranians cuz the Americans aren't
able to protect us.
If I were a leader of Saudi Arabia,
Kuwait, Bahrain, Qatar, Oman, or the
UAE,
I would be seriously reassessing my
country's
relationship with the United States.
Moving on. Shortly after Trump signaled
the US was what it ready to de-escalate,
telling reporters on Air Force One that
Iranian officials had  called a
little while ago and want to make a
deal. That's just simply not true.
The Iranians do not just call and say
they want to make a deal. The Iranians
do not call and say, "Oh, woe are we we
give up. We want peace." No, that's just
made up. That's for domestic US
political consumption.
The Iranians are willing to fight to the
very death to protect their country.
Remember,
and this is important. Don't don't
forget this.
In the very beginning,
when the United States and Israel
launched these decapitation attacks,
they killed Ayatollah Khamenei, they
killed almost every Iranian nuclear
scientist, they killed multiple cabinet
members, they killed just about every
senior member of the Iranian military
leadership. The war was supposed to last
a day, a day, because once these people
were dead, remember, the Iranian people
were going to rise up
and it was going to be the land of milk
and honey and freedom would reign and
everybody would be happy. And that just
never happened.
The thing is is anybody who watches Iran
and Iranian politics could have
predicted that that would never happen.
But, our government decided to listen
to the admonitions of Benjamin Netanyahu
and now we're bogged down in a war that
we can't win.
The other side, Iran's top negotiator
Mohammad Bagher Ghalibaf, accused the US
of bullying and breaking promises and
warned that the Strait of Hormuz would
only reopen on Tehran's terms. Quote,
"If you strike, you'll get hit." That's
what Ghalibaf wrote on X, formerly
Twitter. The Strait of Hormuz will only
open with Iranian arrangements, not
American threats. So, let's let's look
at the Strait of Hormuz. If we can pull
up a a map, JB.
I'm asking my producer to pull up a map
of the Strait of Hormuz. You see how
ships
have to go
in that little over over what's called
the Musandam Peninsula.
Uh now, it's the United Arab Emirates on
the very tip and the rest of it is Oman.
So, so part of that peninsula is
separated from the rest of Oman, but
it's all desert. Almost nobody lives
there. The UAE and Oman are very close,
so it doesn't matter. But, here's the
key. The Strait of Hormuz is very very
shallow and it's very difficult for
ships to maneuver through. Well, the
deepest part of the Strait of Hormuz is
on the Iranian side
of the maritime border.
And so, for the last century plus,
if you wanted to go through the Strait
of Hormuz, you went through Iranian
waters.
And then we started bombing Iran and the
Iranians closed the strait.
Well, then all of a sudden there's a
toll and Donald Trump says, "We are
going to collect the toll." It's not up
to us to do to collect the toll for
ships going through Iranian territorial
waters.
That didn't work. It lasted just a
couple of days.
And then some ships started to try to go
through the the Emirati and Omani side,
but it's very shallow there.
And it's dangerous for ships to run
aground.
Um the Iranians also were angry because
it upset the status quo and the Iranians
then attacked one of those ships then
resulting in renewed US bombing. The
bottom line being we're all back to
square one again.
I want to add this, too.
There was no problem for ships going
through the Strait of Hormuz before the
US attack, the US and Israeli attack. It
was the US and Israeli attack that
closed the Strait of Hormuz. And then
we're demanding that the Strait of
Hormuz be open. The Strait of Hormuz was
open.
We're the ones that forced the closure.
So we're going to have to see where that
goes. I'm hoping cooler heads prevail,
but I'm not optimistic. The big picture,
reopening the Strait of Hormuz and
restoring freedom of navigation for
commercial ships has become a central
goal for the Trump administration mainly
to stabilize global energy markets.
Well, of course it has.
Nobody wants to pay $4 or 4 and a
quarter for a gallon of gas. For Iran,
maintaining control over the Strait has
become a key objective in any deal to
end the war because it belongs to Iran.
The issue was a central provision in the
US-Iran memorandum of understanding and
conflicting interpretations of the
Strait clauses are now causing the deal
to unravel. The MOU requires Iran to
allow safe passage for ships through the
Strait of Hormuz, but soon after it was
signed, Iranian officials accused the US
of violating the deal by routing ships
through the southern lane near the Omani
coast without Tehran's approval. So
there it is.
Lindsey Graham, who we've said died
suddenly Saturday, spent his final weeks
laying the groundwork for an ambitious
new push to normalize relations between
Saudi Arabia and Israel.
This is something that he told the
reporter Barack
what's his name?
Barack Ravid in multiple conversations.
Now,
this would be the crown jewel of the
so-called Abraham Accords. You might
recall in the 2016 presidential
campaign, then candidate Donald Trump
said that he would end the Arab-Israeli
dispute in 24 hours.
Okay, obviously, clearly, that was
ridiculous and he didn't do that. But
what he meant by that
was he was going to just screw the
Palestinians and try to get the Arabs to
open diplomatic relations with the
Israelis. He was largely successful in
what was called the Abraham Accords. So
now, Morocco has relations with Israel,
uh Sudan has relations with Israel,
uh the United Arab Emirates has
relations with Israel, Bahrain has
relations with Israel, in addition to
Egypt and Jordan, which have long had
relations with Israel. But the crown
jewel would be Saudi Arabia. Not just
because Saudi Arabia is the biggest and
most populous country on the Arabian
Peninsula, but because it is what's
called the land of the two holy mosques.
It's the very
beating heart
of Islam.
Also, Lindsey Graham knew darn well
that most Gulf Arabs hate the
Palestinians.
And I'll tell you why they hate the
I was I had a front row seat
to this whole thing playing out.
In 1990, on August 2nd, 1990, Iraq
invaded Kuwait.
The ruling family fled into exile in
Saudi Arabia and Iraqi troops set out to
rape
Kuwaiti women, they destroyed the
country, they set all of the oil wells
on fire, took years to put them out.
Um
But the entire middle class, not just in
Kuwait, was
Palestinian.
The Palestinians were the doctors, the
lawyers, the professors, the bankers.
They made the economies run.
And
the leader of the Palestinians at the
time, or the Palestine Liberation
Organization, was Yasser Arafat.
The American Secretary of State, James
Baker, went to Arafat and said, "You
have to do the right thing. You have to
come down on the side of the Kuwaitis
and help us push the Iraqis out of
Kuwait."
And there was this very public
self-flagellation on the part of Yasser
Arafat, and in the end, he came down on
the side of Saddam Hussein.
The same thing was happening in the
United Nations Security Council at the
time.
Yemen just happened to have a seat that
year on the on the UN Security Council.
And Secretary Baker went to the Yemenis
and said, "If you have any idea what's
good for you, you're going to vote yes
on a use of force to push the Iraqis out
of Kuwait."
The Yemenis
and the Cubans were the only ones to
vote no.
As a result, Saudi Arabia expelled
literally every Yemeni. It was millions
of them. Yemen has never recovered.
Never. The economy collapsed, the
country split, civil war after civil
war, it's never recovered.
But when I was living in the Gulf in the
early and mid-1990s, the consensus among
Gulf royal families was that they were
going to expel every Palestinian.
And for the most part, they did. They
replaced them with Filipinos,
Bangladeshis, Egyptians.
Most recently, Syrians.
You don't have to be Palestinian to be a
lawyer or a professor or an engineer or
a banker. Other countries produce those
professions as well.
And so the Palestinians never recovered.
And that's why
right now
these countries are willing to open
diplomatic relations with the Israel
with the Israelis because
they don't mind screwing the
Palestinians.
Lindsey Graham knew that.
Benjamin Netanyahu certainly knows that.
Donald Trump probably knows it, doesn't
care one way or the other.
And so uh the Palestinians are in a very
bad situation right now.
Now, we get to a point where
we get to a point where
the average American
who watches the news every day
wakes up one morning and says, "Wait a
minute, this is a genocide. You can't
just go there and just kill everybody.
That can't be your policy to kill
everybody, every civilian, every man,
woman, child, elderly person. You you
flatten the hospitals, literally all of
them. You flatten the schools, you
flatten all the homes and the apartment
buildings, and then you restrict food
shipments.
And you cause starvation on a massive
scale.
So it's not our political leaders like
Lindsey Graham who who have stood up.
It's the average American who is
standing up and saying enough. Well,
Lindsey Graham saw Saudi-Israel
normalization as the defining prize of a
broader post-war settlement in the
Middle East, one that could outlast the
military campaign against Iran and then
fundamentally reshape the region. He had
worked on this issue for many years,
including with the Biden administration.
And he believed the opening created by
Iran's weakening could give President
Trump a rare chance to broker a historic
agreement. I will tell you that I have
been guilty
over the past 6 or 8 months of saying
that
this may sound overly optimistic.
But we used to say in the '70s,
only Nixon could go to China. Richard
Nixon was the most anti-communist, most
anti-Chinese president in American
history, but he went to China and made
peace. Would it be possible that only
Trump could go to Tehran?
No.
Lindsey Graham's plan was to begin an
intensive diplomatic push after Israel's
October elections and the US midterms
with the goal of reaching a deal before
the new Congress was sworn in in
January. So time was tight and it was
running out.
But Graham believed the war with Iran
first had to be brought under control,
especially this ongoing crisis in the
Strait of Hormuz. He had urged Donald
Trump to authorize a short, overwhelming
military operation to forcibly reopen
the strait if diplomacy failed.
That sounds like the old troop surge
that we initiated in Iraq and which also
failed. I'm going to leave you with this
thought from Barak Ravid, the Axios
reporter. He says that Graham told him
that he intended to work with President
Trump and his team to make clear to
Netanyahu and to other Israeli leaders
that Washington expected the next
government, the next Israeli government,
to move in the direction of
normalization of relations with Saudi
Arabia and that the US would press it
hard to do so.
In the final hours of his life, Graham
spoke with President Trump by phone
Saturday night. We believe that this was
the final phone call that he had.
And he briefed him on his trip to
Ukraine and on the Russia sanctions bill
that he wanted the Senate to vote on
soon. Trump told Graham that he was
preparing to launch fresh strikes
against Iran after another attack on
commercial ships in the Strait of
Hormuz. A person who spoke with Graham
just after the call said that Graham
complained that he was not feeling well.
When the person urged him to seek
medical attention immediately, Graham
said that he would do so on Sunday
morning after he finished his stint on
Meet the Press. Graham then joked, "I
can't die now. I still need to do the
Russia sanctions, get Iran sorted out,
and do Israel-Saudi normalization."
And then he dropped dead 2 hours later.
I don't believe that anything's going to
change vis-à-vis the war in Iran now
that Lindsey Graham is dead. Donald
Trump has his policy. Donald Trump has
made up his mind. Donald Trump certainly
has the support of the rest of the
Republicans in the House and the Senate
to continue this this war on Iran.
But but he did lose a serious
cheerleader in Lindsey Graham. When I
was a little kid at Christmas time, my
mom and dad always used to put one
little 1-oz silver bar in my stocking
and the stockings of my brother and
sister. And it was fun, and silver was
something like $7 an ounce at the time,
and
I just accumulated them.
I started doing the same thing with my
own kids at Christmas time, putting a
1-oz silver bar. Well, then I discovered
10-oz silver bars. And then there are
the big silver silver bars that are 100
oz.
It's just my way of saying that um we
did that just for fun. We did it at
Christmas time just for fun. But it's
very serious. What if the way money
works is about to change? Not someday,
not hypothetically, but right now. China
and the United States are both making
moves that suggest that we could be
headed towards something the world
hasn't seen in more than 50 years, a
return to gold-backed money or something
very close to it. China is shutting down
paper gold trading at four of its
biggest banks right now, all on the same
day, and they're building a new system
that settles in gold physically instead.
On our side, the government is sitting
on over 8,000 tons of gold still valued
at just $42 an ounce on the books.
Legislation to fix that is already in
Congress. If both superpowers start
anchoring their currencies to gold, what
happens to the price? And more
importantly, what happens to every
dollar in your retirement that isn't
backed by anything at all?
That's the question. Our free report
from American Alternative Assets
answers. It's called The Day Money
Changes Forever. And if you have an IRA
or a 401k, you need to read it right
now.
Get your free copy at johnlovesgold.com.
That's johnlovesgold.com
or you can call toll-free
888-G-O-L-D-0-5-3.
Have you ever wondered what it feels
like to shoot with the same precision
tech used by US special forces? Well,
there's good news. After years of
research and development, MCG Tactical
just dropped something incredible. It's
called the Stinger Combat Sight. This
isn't your average laser red dot. Using
holographic technology once reserved for
elite military and law enforcement, the
Stinger delivers crystal clear
precision, so accurate you could hit a
dime
at 300 yards without even trying. This
is the exact same level of technology
used by the pros.
But here's the twist. Most sights like
this go for 600 bucks or more, and
people happily pay it.
But right now through an exclusive deal
with MCG Tactical, you can get this
military spec site
for under $200. And it gets better. For
my listeners, you're getting 67%
off
and they're covering the shipping. When
I was at the CIA, we actually had a
demonstration once by a special forces
sniper who hit a small balloon at 1,000
yards.
I couldn't believe it.
This is the kind of technology we're
talking about. Just scan the QR code or
go to mcgtac.com/johnsting
to get yours today. That's again
mcgtac.com/johnsting.
The only catch, supply is tight and
these are already flying off the
shelves. So, if you want a site built
for the best, now's your chance to get
it. Grab yours before they have to shut
down orders. That's
mcgtac.com/johnsting.
All right, that was a lot of serious
material and thanks for staying with me
through it. But I want to take a second
to have some fun.
Your fan edits
have blown me away. I really cannot walk
5 ft without getting recognized.
All because someone on TikTok started
adding laser beams to my eyes and uh and
Alvin and the Chipmunks voice when I
talk. I have a personal policy that I
never ever ever say no to a selfie
request or an autograph or whatever.
Because when I say that that my success
is only because of you and people like
you, I mean it.
But anyway, I wanted to show you a
couple of the uh
of the fan edits that are out there that
we've had so much fun with.
Can we cut to some of those?
This is a tattoo.
A tattoo that Chris Riley got on his
leg.
I I didn't even know what to say.
I'm I'm humbled. I'm not sure that
you're going to want a tattoo of my
pouting face
20 years from now, but listen, I'm
humbled and flattered.
>> [laughter]
>> You can't force hummus up someone's
rectum, for example.
Right?
You can't
>> You know, they learned I was afraid of
an irrational fear of insects. And so,
they put him in a coffin.
>> And they dumped a box of cockroaches in
there with him.
And then closed the coffin. And they
left him in there for 10 days just with
a diaper.
>> You can't do that. Nobody told you you
had permission to do something like
that.
You know, and waterboarding was supposed
to be
the ultimate
technique.
But there were a couple that were
that were clearly worse than
waterboarding.
>> Uh sleep deprivation.
Right?
>> So,
this was the first one that I received.
Uh I I didn't even receive it. I just
randomly saw it on Instagram. And
there are a lot of crazy talented people
out there. So, I'm I'm very, very
flattered, but it's just nuts to me that
people are using their talents for silly
things like this. Thank you for Oh my
god. I have an assistant uh who goes
through my emails uh just because I get
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
emails every day. I just can't get
through them.
And she told me the other day, "You
know, you get You get nudes like every
single day." She said, "I just delete,
delete, delete."
And I said, "Yeah, save for that way. I
mean, I don't know if these people are
18 years old and even still, I I don't
want their nudes."
And she said, "Oh, they're between like
18 and 70."
I was like, "Yeah, no. There's even a a
petition that somebody started to put me
on Dancing with the Stars."
>> [laughter]
>> It's just so ridiculous.
I don't even know what to say.
I am
I am grateful though. I really am.
It's fun.
>> Of all these Cameos,
what was the sweetest one?
>> Uh
I've gotten three. I've I've done about
1,950 Cameos so far.
>> Okay.
>> I do 20 or 30 a day.
>> I've gotten three where Well, let me let
me back up. About 50% of them are
birthday wishes. You know, uh
Jimbo's birthday is next Tuesday. I say,
"Hey, happy birthday Jimbo. John
Kiriakou here. Hope you had a great day,
you know, etc."
So, there's birthday, you know, Mother's
Day, Father's Day, whatever.
Advice,
pep talk.
About 10% are pep talks.
So, of the 10% that have been pep talks,
three
have come back to say that I somehow
talked them out of committing suicide.
I'm not really sure how I did that.
But, you know, there are a lot of really
hurting people out there.
We get so wrapped up in our own lives
and our own existences, we don't realize
how many other people are in pain.
There's one girl, she's just one out of
almost 2,000 Cameos that I've done.
One who sounded like she was in such
pain. I said, "Listen." In the Cameo, I
said,
'We're not supposed to do this, but
here's my phone number.
>> Wow.
>> Call me.'
And she called me.
Crying, she's 15.
She's bulimic.
Her parents don't understand her. She
was going to commit suicide.
And I talked her out of it.
And um
she's called me twice since then.
Usually for less than a minute or two.
>> Very respectful.
>> Very, very respectful. And she said she
just She's having a down day and she
needs to hear a friendly voice.
And that's it.
Cameo has literally changed my life. Uh
Cameo is an app where, you know,
D-list celebrities,
people most Americans have never heard
of like me, um
will give you birthday wishes, as I
said, or or a pep talk or advice, or,
you know, happy Father's Day or Merry
Christmas or whatever.
But every once in a while, you know,
people who are really in crisis reach
out because it's the only way they can
figure out how to get to you,
and then one thing leads to the other. I
I will add that during COVID, I had a
friend, a good friend, who took his own
life.
And I spoke to him the day before
he did that.
And
he sounded great. And I said to him,
"James, you sound great today." He was
He was depressed a lot.
And he said, "Yeah, I feel really good
today."
The next day his sister called me.
And um
and she said, "I wanted you to know that
James killed himself last night."
He um
he went for a walk in the neighborhood.
The neighbor had a big oak tree.
He strung up a noose and he hung himself
from the neighbor's oak tree.
He left a note. He said he didn't want
to
get his mom's house dirty.
But he said,
"Please call John and tell him I said I
was sorry."
I will never forgive myself
thinking that there was something I
could have done, something I could have
said to talk him out of it. Again, I had
talked him out of it, I don't know how
many times.
But
it made me realize how many people are
out there who are genuinely hurting.
And if they need a friendly voice,
and I happen to be that friendly voice,
I'm happy to do it.
We've got to rely on each other. I think
COVID really
really showed that to all of us that we
have to help each other and stick
together to get through these tough
times. We can't just be focused on our
own lives and stuck on our own zone when
there are other people out there who
really need help.
And so I I was glad that I could help
somebody.
I am addicted to Angry Birds. My ex-wife
once told me that one of the reasons why
she wanted divorce was because as soon
as my alarm goes off in the morning, I
roll over, put on my glasses, pick up my
phone, and I start playing Angry Birds.
And she would lose her mind on me. "What
are you doing? Are you playing Angry
Birds again? Is that all you do is play
Angry Birds?" In my defense, I actually
get up an hour early. Nobody's missing
out on anything. I'd rather have Angry
Birds than have you. I'm globally ranked
on Angry Birds. I have played 2,887
consecutive days. A guy said to me the
other day, "Hey, I made level 36 in
Angry Birds. What level are you?" I
said, "1,708."
Angry Birds is very important to me.
>> [laughter]
>> The more
podcasts I'm on, the more people ask me
about my personal life. And one of the
things that I love, love, love, it's
really my only vice, besides buying art,
um is playing Angry Birds. Angry Birds
2.
I have not missed a single day in nine
consecutive years. I love Angry Birds.
It's the first thing I do when I wake up
in the morning. I roll over, I put on my
glasses, I get my phone, I go to Angry
Birds, and I start killing those pigs
that are eating my birds' eggs.
And of course, I use the black pearls
that I accumulate to buy hats for my
birds, and I increase the number of
feathers, so their flock strength is
more, and you have to You have to know
Angry Birds to really understand, but
man, there is nothing that I love more
than Angry Birds. You got to love Angry
Birds. It's For For a while, it was like
the only joy I had in life.
And sure enough, the first thing I did
this morning was play Angry Birds. I
will add that my doctor, last time I
went in for a physical, my doctor said,
"You know, you're 61, you're almost 62,
you need to start thinking about keeping
your brain fresh." And I said, "Okay,
what do you mean by that?" And he said,
"I want you to do the New York Times
crossword puzzle every day." I said,
"Every day, including Saturday?" Cuz
that's like an impossible puzzle.
He said, "Yeah, do it every day."
I've become obsessed with crossword
puzzles. I do the Washington Post, which
is really the LA Times. I do the New
York Times, and I do the USA Today every
single day, 7 days a week. So now I have
to actually get up even earlier because
I do the I do the crossword puzzles
first, and then I do Angry Birds.
Because Angry Birds, you know, I can
take breaks and, you know, whatever.
Check out Angry Birds. You can't go
wrong.
In the meantime, I I want to thank you
again for joining us. This was our very
first episode of uh of The Briefing
Room, and as I said, I'm going to say it
again, we're only able to do this
because of you. So please like,
comment, share, rate, review, and tell
your friends and family. The plan is to
release new videos every Tuesday and
Thursday. But, one of the things that I
absolutely love to do is to take
questions from you. And so, please feel
free to put questions in the chat, and
then we will begin answering them in a
third installment uh during the course
of the week. I look forward to that very
much.
Just let the questions rip, and we'll
handle them as they come. Thanks for
joining us, and we'll see you next time.